Guide to the Carl Van Vechten Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1907-1971; Series I; 79.8; 183 boxes
  - A-Z Correspondence
    - De Mille, Agnes, 1930–1965 (Box 34, Folder 470)
      Includes two letters from Anna George de Mille to CVV (1930, 1937)
    - De Vecchi, Margherita, 1954–1964 (Box 34, Folder 471)
    - Dearly, Max, undated (Box 34, Folder 472)
    - Delteil, Caroline Dudley, 1934–1959 (Box 34, Folder 473)
      Includes photograph of Delteil and her husband Joseph Delteil enclosed with letter to CVV (1934); photograph of Joseph Delteil with note on verso (1959); typed transcript, carbon copy, of letter to Caroline Delteil from Henry Miller enclosed with letter from Delteil to CVV (1959)
    - Demuth, Charles, 1922–1959 (Box 34, Folder 474)
      Includes one letter from Demuth to CVV (1922); third party letters regarding Demuth from Whitney Museum of American Art (1937-1938), Emily Farnam (1956), Jean Burkholder (1958), and Jeanne V. Halsey (1959)
    - Denman, Phil, 1955–1965 (Box 34, Folder 475)
    - Deutsch, Helen, 1932–1933 (Box 35, Folder 476)
    - The Dial, 1917–1924 (Box 35, Folder 477)
      Includes letters to CVV signed by George Bernard Donlin, Gilbert Seldes, and Alyse Gregory
    - Dickson, Charles, 1920 September 7 (Box 35, Folder 478)
    - Dinesen, Isak
      See: Blixen, Karen
    - Dixon, Jean, 1934; 1964 (Box 35, Folder 479)
      Letter and telegram to FM
    - Dodd, Mead & Company, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 480)
    - Dolin, Anton, 1940–1953 (Box 35, Folder 481)
    - Dolmetsch, Carl R. (Carl Richard), 1955–1964 (Box 35, Folder 482)
    - Donahoe, Edward
      - 1937–1942 (Box 35, Folder 483-489)
        Includes photograph of the front door of Donahoe's home, enclosed with letter to CVV (1938)
      - "Head of Scopas", 1942 (Box 181 (Oversize), Folder 2308)
        Clipping of "Head by Scopas" by Donahoe, published in Space, July, 1934, previously enclosed with 1942 February 27 letter from Donahoe to CVV
      - 1943–1961 (Box 36, Folder 490-497)
        Includes third-party letter from Dick Griffith to Donahoe, enclosed with letter from Donahoe to CVV (1961); photo booth photographs of Donahoe enclosed with letter to CVV (1961); photograph of "Buster Blue," a Siamese cat, enclosed with letter to CVV (1961)
      - 1962–1965 (Box 37, Folder 498-506)
        Includes letter signed by Donahoe, Donald Cordry, Dorothy Cordry, and Fredericka Martin to CVV (1962)
    - Dorn, Marion V., 1936-1949, undated (Box 38, Folder 507)
    - Doro, Marie, 1919-1957, undated (Box 38, Folder 508-512)
      Includes third-party letters relating to Doro's death (1956-1957)
    - Double Dealer, 1921-1923, undated (Box 38, Folder 513)
    - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1949; 1963 (Box 38, Folder 514)
    - Doubleday, Page & Company, 1916 (Box 38, Folder 515)
    - Douglas, Barbara, 1962; 1964 (Box 38, Folder 516)
      Includes two photographs of Douglas, her husband Lloyd, and children, enclosed with letter from Douglas to FM (1962)
    - Douglas, Mahala, 1924–1945 (Box 38, Folder 517-518)
    - Douglas, Norman, undated (Box 39, Folder 519)
    - Dow, Dorothy, 1947 (Box 39, Folder 520)
    - Dowell, Coleman, 1958-1967, undated (Box 39, Folder 521-522)
      Includes correspondence signed "Cole and Bert" (Bertram Slaff); lyrics, typescript, undated, to "You Take Paris (Ella)" by Dowell, enclosed with letter from Dowell to CVV (1960)
    - Dowling, Robert W., 1962 (Box 39, Folder 523)
    - Downing, Robert
      - 1930–1955 (Box 39, Folder 524-530)
        Includes, "The Anonymous Cats of 'A Streetcar Named Desire'" by Robert Downing, typescript carbon copy, enclosed with letter from Downing to CVV (1951)
      - The Pulse, 1930 November 7 (Box 181 (Oversize), Folder 2309)
        Issue of The Pulse, the Washington Senior High School of Cedar Rapids, Iowa student newspaper, previously enclosed with 1930 November 12 letter from Downing to CVV
      - 1956–1964 (Box 40, Folder 531-538)
        Includes typescript of dialogue deleted from the Stage Door Canteen production number at event honoring Helen Hayes, enclosed with letter from Downing to CVV (1956); clippings and offprints of Downing articles
    - Dramatists Play Agency, 1917 October 8 (Box 41, Folder 539)
    - Draper, Muriel, 1924-1944, undated (Box 41, Folder 540-541)
      Includes third-party letter from Tom Howard to CVV (1934); third-party gift acknowledgement from the New York Public Library to Draper, enclosed with note from Draper to CVV, and undated letter to Draper signed "R.E.F.L." (1944)
    - Draper, Paul, 1952; 1964 (Box 41, Folder 542)
    - Dreiser, Theodore
      See also: Photoduplicated letters from CVV to Dreiser in Box 176
      - 1906–1964 (Box 41, Folder 543-544)
        Includes "Memory, A Rondel," autograph poem, signed, by Harris Merton Lyon, stamped "Broadway Magazine Nov 14 1906"; typescript letter, carbon copy, from Rex Beach, Chairman of the Author's League to Dreiser, Dreiser's answer to Beach, and Gelett Burgess's response to Dreiser (1923); typescript essay, carbon copy, regarding the Scottsboro case and typed letter, mimeograph copy, from International Labor Defense enclosed with letter from Dreiser's secretary to CVV (1932); typed letter, signed, from Mrs. Dreiser to CVV (1950); third-party letters regarding Dreiser (1963-1964)
      - Forward to Dreiser's The "Genius", 1923 (Box 182 (Oversize), Folder 2330)
        Galley proofs of the forward to the 1923 edition of The "Genius, " previously enclosed with 1923 September 15 third-party letter from Boni & Liveright, Inc. publishers to CVV
    - Drezovsky, Luba, 1953–1963 (Box 41, Folder 545)
    - Duchamp, Marcel, 1917–1947 (Box 41, Folder 546)
    - Dudensing, Valentine, 1929–1958 (Box 41, Folder 547)
      Includes correspondence signed by Dudensing's wife, Bibi Dudensing; third-party letter from Allan Herschell Company, Inc. to Bibi Dudensing (1937)
    - Dufty, William, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 548)
      Includes photograph of Dufty's son, Bevan with Billie Holiday dated 1957, and an undated note in the hand of Holiday, enclosed with Dufty's letter to CVV (1960 May 4)
    - Duke, Vernon, 1957; 1964 (Box 41, Folder 549)
    - Duval, Jean-Jacques, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 550)
      Includes correspondence signed by Duval's wife, Elga Liverman Duval
    - Dymow, Ossip, 1917 July 12 (Box 41, Folder 551)
    - "E" General, 1915-1963, undated (Box 41, Folder 552-553)
    - E. Leitz, Inc., 1932–1935 (Box 42, Folder 554)
    - Earl, Bill, 1960–1964 (Box 42, Folder 555-558)
      Includes "Invasion of a Rehearsal," typescript carbon copy, by Earl, enclosed with note to CVV (1961); photograph of Earl's wife Helen Kane enclosed with letter from Earl to CVV (1963); photograph of Earl performing in the ballet "Persephony" enclosed with letter to CVV (1964)
    - Eastman Kodak Company, 1932–1962 (Box 42, Folder 559)
    - Edison, Sidney, 1952–1957 (Box 42, Folder 560)
    - Ehrman, Lillian May, 1935, undated (Box 42, Folder 561)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1946 May 23 (Box 42, Folder 562)
      Telegram regarding atomic power
    - Eisenstein, Abraham, 1959 February 3 (Box 42, Folder 563)
    - Elder, Eldon, 1960; 1962 (Box 42, Folder 564)
    - Elder, Judith, 1951–1952 (Box 42, Folder 565)
    - Ellis, Mary, undated (Box 42, Folder 566)
    - Elliston, Grace, 1916 May 1 (Box 42, Folder 567)
    - Elvander, Lucile, 1959 September 12 (Box 42, Folder 568)
    - Emerson, John, 1931 July 25 (Box 42, Folder 569)
      Postcard to FM
    - Emery, Gilbert, 1925; 1932; undated (Box 42, Folder 570)
    - Emmet, Katherine, 1934 September 12 (Box 42, Folder 571)
    - Emmett, Robert, 1960–1965 (Box 42, Folder 572)
      Includes notes signed by Emmett's wife, Kim Hunter
    - Encyclopaedia Britannica, inc., 1929–1956 (Box 42, Folder 573)
    - Epstein, Jacob, 1929; 1932; undated (Box 42, Folder 574)
      Includes receipt for payment for the "bronze head of Paul Robeson" enclosed with note to CVV from Epstein (1929)
    - Equity League, 1964 (Box 42, Folder 575)
    - Equity Players, 1924 June 2 (Box 42, Folder 576)
    - Ercolini, Mary Alice, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 577)
    - Esquire, 1957–1963 (Box 42, Folder 578)
    - Evans, Donald
      - 1913–1914 (Box 42, Folder 579-580)
        Includes a piece of fabric "[Hans] Schmidt bought for wrapping up Anna Aumuller's body in" enclosed with note from Evans to CVV (1913); "Dinner at the Hotel de la Tigre Vert," typescript poem by Evans, with autograph note below the poem, enclosed with letter from Evans to CVV (1914 July 19); the same poem with one autograph manuscript change, enclosed with Evan's letter to CVV (1914 August 16)
      - 1915–1921 (Box 43, Folder 581-583)
        Includes proof of "Loving Kindness, Moscow," by Evans, enclosed with note to FM, for whom the poem was written (1915); printed information regarding A Hundred Idle Fellows membership enclosed with letter from Evans to CVV (1915)
        See also: Harvard College Library
    - Evans, F. W., 1901 May 18 (Box 43, Folder 584)
      Letter from Evans, Denver, Colorado, to Michael Marinoff, Crete, Nebraska, regarding FM
    - Evans, Montgomery, 1924–1950 (Box 43, Folder 585)
      Includes autograph letters and photographic postcards, signed, by CVV to Evans (1924-1941); "Madame de Sévigné is Dead," typescript essay about a cat, by Evans, enclosed with photographs of the cat and a note from Evans to CVV (1945); additional photographs of cats enclosed with correspondence (1948-1950)
      Source of letters from CVV to Evans unknown
    - Ewing, Doris, 1924-1946, undated (Box 43, Folder 586-587)
      Includes autograph and typed letters and photographic postcards, signed, by CVV to Ewing (1924-1943, undated); typescript "Letters from Doris Ewing to Carl Van Vechten in reply to questions from the latter, regarding Max Ewing and his family" (1942); Ewing Family tree and map of Pioneer, Ohio drawn by Doris Ewing, enclosed with letter to CVV (1942); fragment of a published Michigan road map with several towns circled in red pencil (1942?); photograph of Ewing enclosed with letter to CVV (1946)
      Letters from CVV to Ewing purchased from Mel B. Yoken, 2000
    - Ewing, Max
      - 1922–1932 (Box 43, Folder 588-591)
        Includes "Alchemy in Fairfax Arms," typescript sonnet by Ewing for CVV, enclosed with letter from Ewing to CVV (1923); typescript list of people and places, annotated and signed by Ewing (1932); photograph of Ewing with Herbert Buch, and Ewing with Joe Gould, enclosed with note from Ewing to CVV (1932)
      - 1933-1950, undated (Box 44, Folder 592-593)
        Includes third-party letters from Ewing family members and friends A.E. Ewing, Doris Ewing, and Dorothy Sheldon to CVV regarding Max Ewing's death (1934-1939); letter from William John McAfee to CVV requesting permission to see Ewing's papers (1950)
    - Eyck, Peter van, 1940 April 12 (Box 44, Folder 594)
    - "F" General, 1908-1964, undated (Box 44, Folder 595-598)
    - Farrar, John, 1935–1963 (Box 44, Folder 599)
    - Farrar, Straus, and Cudahy, 1950; 1960 (Box 44, Folder 600)
    - Feibleman, Peter S., 1958–1961 (Box 44, Folder 601)
      Includes typed letter, signed, from CVV to Feibleman, enclosed with Feibleman's letter to CVV (1959)
    - Ferber, Edna, 1938-1949, undated (Box 44, Folder 602)
    - Ferguson, Helen, 1965 January 1 (Box 44, Folder 603)
    - Ferguson, Nancy
      See: Arenstein, Yetta
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison
      See also: Photoduplicated letters from Ficke to CVV in Box 176
      - 1920–1925 (Box 44, Folder 604-605)
        Includes "On Finishing a Book -- To Donald Evans," typescript poem, with note and initialed by Ficke (1921); photographic postcard of Ficke, Edna St. Vincent Millay and Eugene Boissevain (1923); three photographs of Ficke's home in New Mexico (1925)
      - 1927–1947 (Box 45, Folder 606-610)
        Includes photographs of Ficke and a landscape enclosed with letter from Ficke to CVV (1926); photographs of a Zia Pueblo pot and Andrew Dasburg, Gladys Ficke and Tomasine Fabri with shelves of pottery in background (1926); letters written by Ficke in rhyme to CVV (1938-1939); photograph of a female nude torso enclosed with letter from Ficke to CVV (1939); "The Author of Roosevelt's Speeches," autograph poem, signed by Ficke (1941); photograph of a swimming pool in a rural setting, enclosed with letter from Ficke to CVV (1943)
        See also: Evans, Donald (1942)
    - Ficke, Gladys, 1933-1964, undated (Box 45, Folder 611-613)
      Includes typescript letter, draft, from Ficke to Mr. [Alfred] Knopf enclosed with letter from Ficke to CVV (1948); "Jesus Christ" and "In the Country are Alarms," typescript poems by Ficke enclosed with letter from Ficke to CVV (1952)
    - Field, Betty, 1949-1956, undated (Box 45, Folder 614)
    - Finley, Robert E., 1958–1959 (Box 45, Folder 615)
      Includes "Distant Magpies: Studies in the Theatre of Gertrude Stein," typescript essay, signed by Robert E. Finley, enclosed with letter to CVV (1958); typed gift acknowledgement, carbon copy, from Donald Gallup to Finley (1958)
    - Firmage, George James, 1951–1954 (Box 45, Folder 616)
    - Fisher, Robert C., 1954–1965 (Box 46, Folder 617-618)
      Includes photograph of Fisher and his dog, enclosed with letter from Fisher to CVV (1962)
    - Fisk, Earl E., 1928–1947 (Box 46, Folder 619)
    - Fiske, Dwight, 1937–1939 (Box 46, Folder 620)
    - Fitch, Charles Lewis, 1919 January 29 (Box 46, Folder 621)
      Includes typed transcripts of Fitch family letters
    - Fitch Family Association, 1928–1935 (Box 46, Folder 622)
    - Fitelson, H. William, 1957–1964 (Box 46, Folder 623)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1924-1964, undated (Box 46, Folder 624-625)
      Includes Fitzgerald's letters to CVV (1924-1937) and third-party letters regarding Fitzgerald 's papers and permission to publish CVV's photographs of him (1948-1964)
      See also: Photoduplicated letters from Fitzgerald to CVV in Box 176
    - Fitzgerald, Zelda, 1927–1948 (Box 46, Folder 626)
      Includes telegrams and notes signed Scott and Zelda; third-party letter from Cary Ross to CVV (1934); brochure for an exhibit of Fitzgerald's paintings in New York (1934)
    - Fizdale, Robert, 1951–1952 (Box 46, Folder 627)
    - Flack, Frank M., 1951–1964 (Box 46, Folder 628)
    - Flanner, Janet, 1951–1967 (Box 46, Folder 629)
      Includes typed letter, carbon copy, unsigned, from unidentified correspondent to Flanner (1951); typed draft of letter, with corrections, from FM to Flanner (1966)
    - Fletcher, Richard D., 1948–1965 (Box 46, Folder 630-631)
    - Fontanne, Lynn
      See: Alfred Lunt
    - Forbes, James, 1913 July 24 (Box 46, Folder 632)
    - Ford, Charles Henri, 1933–1964 (Box 46, Folder 633-634)
      Includes typescript blurb for "I Will Be What I am, A Documentary Portrait" by Ford, enclosed with note from Ford to CVV (1948)
    - Ford, Ruth, 1935-1963, undated (Box 47, Folder 635-638)
      Includes notes from Ford's husband Zachary Scott, and Shelley Scott, Ford's daughter with former husband Peter Van Eyck
      See also: Scott, Zachary
    - Forester, Paul, 1943 (Box 47, Folder 639-640)
      Includes correspondence, typescript drafts, and notes regarding "Brains Are For the Asking," a proposed radio show with CVV as a guest
    - Fortune, 1934 (Box 47, Folder 641)
    - Fourcade, Xavier, 1951; 1957 (Box 47, Folder 642)
    - Foy, Gray, 1950–1963 (Box 47, Folder 643)
    - Frank, Morris, 1902-1917, undated (Box 47, Folder 644)
    - Frank, Waldo
      See: The Seven Arts
    - Frankenberg, Lloyd, 1951–1965 (Box 47, Folder 645)
      Includes correspondence from Frankenberg's wife, Loren MacIver; "How to Be Read," typescript review of Gertrude Stein's A Novel of Thank You, by Frankenberg, enclosed with letter to CVV (1959)
    - Franklyn, Roy, 1956–1962 (Box 47, Folder 646)
      Includes correspondence regarding stage productions of Gertrude Stein works at the Interplayers theater and Playhouse Repertory Company in San Francisco
    - Fredericks, Claude, 1950–1964 (Box 47, Folder 647)
      Includes correspondence signed as "Zawy"; photographic postcard of Fredericks with note signed by Jimmy (1950)
      See also: Banyan Press
    - Freedley, George, 1943–1967 (Box 48, Folder 648)
      Includes typed form letter with resume of Freedley from Abraham Mandelstam to CVV (1946); correspondence co-signed by Ed Burke and Freedley; galley proofs for More Mr. Cat and a Bit of Amber Too, pages 1-7, by Freedley, enclosed with letter from Howard Frisch to CVV (1962)
      See also: New York Public Library
    - Freedley, Vinton, 1946; 1959 (Box 48, Folder 649)
      Note and telegram to FM
    - Freedman, Harold, 1934; 1964 (Box 48, Folder 650)
      Telegrams to FM co-signed by May Freedman
    - Frohman, Daniel, 1908-1934, undated (Box 48, Folder 651)
      Includes autograph essay fragment about Victorien Sardou by Frohman (undated)
    - Frohman, Mae, 1953; 1955; undated (Box 48, Folder 652)
    - "G" General, 1910-1964, undated (Box 48, Folder 653-656)
      Includes photographs of paintings of Lucien Coutaud from Galerie de Beaune Tableaux Modernes, Paris (1939)
    - Gallup, Donald, 1947–1970 (Box 48, Folder 657-659)
      Includes correspondence signed Donald III; autograph letter, signed, from FM to Gallup (1069)
      See also: Yale University Library
    - Garden, Mary, 1908-1962, undated (Box 48, Folder 660)
      Includes letter from William A. H. Birnie to Garden enclosed with letter from Garden to CVV (1946); letter from William Raney to CVV (1947); letter from Herbert Weinstock to Garden enclosed with letter from Garden to CVV (1947)
    - Garland, Robert, 1915–1953 (Box 49, Folder 661)
    - Gateson, Marjorie, 1951; 1964; undated (Box 49, Folder 662)
    - Gauthier, Eva, 1945–1957 (Box 49, Folder 663)
    - Gaya, Richard F., 1953 (Box 49, Folder 664)
    - Gaydos, Thomas, 1959–1964 (Box 49, Folder 665)
    - George, George Edward, 1943–1965 (Box 49, Folder 666-671)
      Includes autograph and typed letters, signed by CVV to George (1943-1955); photographs of George enclosed with George's letters to CVV (1943-1945); typed letter, signed from CVV to "Edward XII" and to "George I" and "Edward XII" (1945); autograph letter, signed by Philippe Jullian to CVV enclosed with letter from George to CVV (1949)
      CVV letters to George were the gift of George George, 1980
    - George H. Doran Company, 1916–1926 (Box 49, Folder 672)
    - Gershwin, George, 1936; 1959 (Box 49, Folder 673)
      Includes one typed letter, signed, from Gershwin to CVV (1936) and two letters from Robert Payne to CVV regarding Gershwin (1959)
    - Gertz, Elmer, 1929; 1935 (Box 49, Folder 674)
    - Gilder, Rosamond, 1937-1965, undated (Box 49, Folder 675)
      Includes a photograph of a barn Gilder built in Lee, Massachusetts, enclosed with letter from Gilder to CVV (1943)
    - Gillmore, Margalo, 1923–1964 (Box 49, Folder 676)
    - Gish, Lillian, 1930-1966, undated (Box 49, Folder 677)
      Includes telegram from Dorothy Gish and Romney Brent to FM (1935); note from Dorothy Gish to CVV and FM (1950)
    - Glasgow, Ellen, 1924–1960 (Box 50, Folder 678-683)
      Includes typescript comments regarding the death of Glasgow, with manuscript note, "Mr. Mumford of Richmond to Mark Lutz" (1945?); letter from Anne Virginia Bennett to CVV (1946); third-party letters to CVV regarding Glasgow's papers (1956-1960); typescript "Calendar of Letters to Ellen Glasgow in the Alderman Library" of the University of Virginia enclosed with letter from Oliver L. Steele to CVV (1960)
    - Glaspell, Susan, 1926 July 28 (Box 50, Folder 684)
    - Glenn, Isa, 1925–1932 (Box 50, Folder 685)
      Includes letter to CVV from Glenn's son, Bayard Schindel (1929); typed transcript, carbon copy, of letter to Glenn from Nella Larsen Imes (1931)
    - Goldberg, Penny, 1962–1964 (Box 50, Folder 686)
      Includes correspondence signed by Goldberg's husband, Robert Goldberg
    - Goldman, Emma, 1934–1940 (Box 50, Folder 687)
      Includes typed transcriptions of letters to Goldman from Edward H. Zabriskie, Ernest L. Meyer, and Mariano R. Vazquez (1934-1939); two copies of a 70th birthday pamphlet (1939); and form letters in support of Goldman (1940)
    - Goldwater, Walter, 1940; 1942 (Box 50, Folder 688)
      Includes typed transcript, carbon copy, of postcard from M. P. Shiel to Goldwater (1942)
    - Goodall, Grace, 1933–1940 (Box 50, Folder 689)
    - Goodman, Edward, 1915–1936 (Box 50, Folder 690)
    - Goodwin, John, 1949; 1953 (Box 50, Folder 691)
    - Goosens, Eugene, 1926–1944 (Box 50, Folder 692)
      Includes correspondence signed, "Boonie"
    - Gordon, John D.
      - 1948–1955 (Box 50, Folder 693-694)
        Includes letters and notes from Gordon's wife, Phyllis Gordon; autograph letters, signed, and telegram from A. A. Berg to CVV (1949-1950); offprint of article by Gordon's wife, Phyllis Gordon enclosed with letter
      - 1956-1971, undated (Box 51, Folder 695-698)
        Includes sheet with photographs of the Gordon children and note from Phyllis Gordon (1961)
    - Gorer, Geoffrey, 1935–1937 (Box 51, Folder 699)
    - Gotham Book Mart, 1939–1964 (Box 51, Folder 700)
      Includes "More Laurels for Our Gertrude," typescript essay with corrections, by CVV (1963)
    - Graeve, Mary Ann, undated (Box 51, Folder 701)
    - Grau Sala, Emilio, 1936–1940 (Box 51, Folder 702)
      Letters to FM, including typed transcripts of letters from "GL to HSTG" (1936) and "MP to HSTG" (1937); seven ink and watercolor drawings for greeting cards (1940)
    - Grausman, Philip, 1961–1968 (Box 51, Folder 703-704)
      Includes photograph of CVV in Grausman's studio, enclosed with Grausman's letter to CVV (1962); photographs of Grausman and his sculptures, enclosed with letter from Grausman to CVV (1963); photographic postcard of Grausman with note to FM (1965); The Alpha Gallery, Boston, catalog of works by Grausman (1968)
    - Grausman, Roland I., 1959–1970 (Box 51, Folder 705)
    - Gray, Maria, 1962–1964 (Box 51, Folder 706)
    - Green, Julien, 1929-1959, undated (Box 51, Folder 707)
      Includes two letters from Robert de Saint-Jean to CVV (1929); letter from Green's sister, Anne Green, to CVV (1950)
    - Greenwood, Marianne, 1962–1965 (Box 51, Folder 708)
    - Grey, Jane, 1920 May 24 (Box 51, Folder 709)
    - Griffis, Stanton, 1937–1941 (Box 52, Folder 710)
      Includes photograph from party for John Latouche enclosed with letter from Griffis to CVV (1941)
    - Grigsby, Emilie, 1929–1953 (Box 52, Folder 711-712)
    - Grimes, Tammy, 1960–1961 (Box 52, Folder 713)
    - Grosser, Maurice, 1939-1953, undated (Box 52, Folder 714)
      Includes photograph of Grosser's painting of Jules Poncin, a sailor (1939?); cancelled check from CVV to Grosser (1939)
    - Grossman, Max, 1964 October 29 (Box 52, Folder 715)
    - Grunewald, Bernhardt, 1960–1964 (Box 52, Folder 716)
      Includes notes signed by Grunewald and his wife Marion Grunewald; photograph of Marion Grunewald, enclosed with note from Grunewald to FM (1964)
    - Guilbert, Yvette, 1917–1940 (Box 52, Folder 717)
    - Guinan, Texas, 1930 May 20 (Box 52, Folder 718)
    - Gysin, Brion, 1947-1960, undated (Box 52, Folder 719)
      Includes typescript outline, carbon copy, of Fulbright fellowship proposal by Gysin, enclosed with letter from Gysin to CVV (1949)
    - "H" General, 1908-1964, undated (Box 52, Folder 720-726)
    - Haas, Dolly, 1955–1970 (Box 53, Folder 727-728)
      Includes letters from Haas's daughter Nina Hirschfeld (1959-1963), and card with note from Haas's husband, the caricaturist Al Hirschfeld (undated)
    - Haas, Robert Bartlett, 1939–1956 (Box 53, Folder 729-730)
      Includes photograph of a harpsichord enclosed with letter from Hass to CVV (1945)
    - Haggin, B.H. (Bernard H.), 1947–1959 (Box 53, Folder 731)